// script.js

let questions = [
    {
        prompt: ` The type name/reserved word ‘short’ is ___`,
        options: [
            "short long",
            "short char",
            "short float",
            "short int",
        ],        

       answer: "short int",
    },
    {
        prompt: `Inside which HTML 
                 element do we put 
                 the JavaScript?`,
        options: [
            "<javascript>",
            "<js>",
            "<script>",
            "<scripting>",
        ],
        answer: "<script>",
    },
    {
        prompt: `A single line comment in C language source code can begin with _____`,
        options: [
            ";",
            "//",
            "/*",
            ":",
        ],
        answer: "//",
    },    
    {
        prompt: `How do you call a
                 function named 
                 myFunction?`,
        options: [
            "call myFunction()",
            "myFunction()",
            "call function myFunction",
            "Call.myFunction",
        ],
        answer: "myFunction()",
    },

    {
        prompt: `How does a for loop
                 start?`,
        options: [
            "for (i = 0; i <= 5; i++)",
            "for (i = 0; i <= 5)",
            "for i = 1 to 5",
            " for (i <= 5; i++)",
        ],
        answer: "for (i = 0; i <= 5; i++)",
    },

    {
        prompt: `In JavaScript, which 
                 of the following is 
                 a logical operator?`,
        options: ["|", "&&", "%", "/"],
        answer: "&&",
    },

    {
        prompt: `A named element in a 
                 JavaScript program that
                 is used to store and 
                 retrieve data is a _____.`,
        options: [
            "method",
            "assignment operator",
            "letiable",
            "string",
        ],
        answer: "letiable",
    },
    {
        prompt: `Which of the following is the use of id() function in python? `,
        options: [
            "Id returns the identity of the object",
            "Every object doesn’t have a unique id ",
            "All of the mentioned",
            "None of the mentioned",
        ],
        answer: "Id returns the identity of the object",
    },


   {
    prompt: ` Which of the following cannot be passed to a function in C++ ? `,
    options: [
        "Constant",
        "Header file",
        "Array",
        "Structure",
    ],
    answer: "Header file",
    },
    {
        prompt: ` What is the Output of following program? a = 4.5 b = 2 print a//b `,
        options: [
            "2",
            "5",
            "2.0",
            "8.4",
        ],
        answer: "2.0",
    },
    {
        prompt: `What command do you use to output data to the screen?`,
        options: [
            "Cin<<",
            "Count>>",
            "Output>>",
            "Count<<",
        ],
        answer: "Count<<",
    },

];

// Get Dom Elements

let questionsEl =
    document.querySelector(
        "#questions"
    );
let timerEl =
    document.querySelector("#timer");
let choicesEl =
    document.querySelector("#options");
let submitBtn = document.querySelector(
    "#submit-score"
);
let startBtn =
    document.querySelector("#start");
let nameEl =
    document.querySelector("#name");
let feedbackEl = document.querySelector(
    "#feedback"
);
let reStartBtn =
    document.querySelector("#restart");

// Quiz's initial state
let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let time = questions.length * 15;
let timerId;

// Start quiz and hide frontpage

function quizStart() {
    timerId = setInterval(
        clockTick,
        1000
    );
    timerEl.textContent = time;
    let landingScreenEl =
        document.getElementById(
            "start-screen"
        );
    landingScreenEl.setAttribute(
        "class",
        "hide"
    );
    questionsEl.removeAttribute(
        "class"
    );
    getQuestion();
}

// Loop through array of questions and
// Answers and create list with buttons
function getQuestion() {
    let currentQuestion =
        questions[currentQuestionIndex];
    let promptEl =
        document.getElementById(
            "question-words"
        );
    promptEl.textContent =
        currentQuestion.prompt;
    choicesEl.innerHTML = "";
    currentQuestion.options.forEach(
        function (choice, i) {
            let choiceBtn =
                document.createElement(
                    "button"
                );
            choiceBtn.setAttribute(
                "value",
                choice
            );
            choiceBtn.textContent =
                i + 1 + ". " + choice;
            choiceBtn.onclick =
                questionClick;
            choicesEl.appendChild(
                choiceBtn
            );
        }
    );
}

// Check for right answers and deduct
// Time for wrong answer, go to next question

function questionClick() {
    if (
        this.value !==
        questions[currentQuestionIndex]
            .answer
    ) {
        time -= 10;
        if (time < 0) {
            time = 0;
        }
        timerEl.textContent = time;
        feedbackEl.textContent = `Wrong! The correct answer was 
        ${questions[currentQuestionIndex].answer}.`;
        feedbackEl.style.color = "red";
    } else {
        feedbackEl.textContent =
            "Correct!";
        feedbackEl.style.color =
            "green";
    }
    feedbackEl.setAttribute(
        "class",
        "feedback"
    );
    setTimeout(function () {
        feedbackEl.setAttribute(
            "class",
            "feedback hide"
        );
    }, 2000);
    currentQuestionIndex++;
    if (
        currentQuestionIndex ===
        questions.length
    ) {
        quizEnd();
    } else {
        getQuestion();
    }
}

// End quiz by hiding questions,
// Stop timer and show final score

function quizEnd() {
    clearInterval(timerId);
    let endScreenEl =
        document.getElementById(
            "quiz-end"
        );
    endScreenEl.removeAttribute(
        "class"
    );
    let finalScoreEl =
        document.getElementById(
            "score-final"
        );
    finalScoreEl.textContent = time;
    questionsEl.setAttribute(
        "class",
        "hide"
    );
}

// End quiz if timer reaches 0

function clockTick() {
    time--;
    timerEl.textContent = time;
    if (time <= 0) {
        quizEnd();
    }
}

// Save score in local storage
// Along with users' name

function saveHighscore() {
    let name = nameEl.value.trim();
    if (name !== "") {
        let highscores =
            JSON.parse(
                window.localStorage.getItem(
                    "highscores"
                )
            ) || [];
        let newScore = {
            score: time,
            name: name,
        };
        highscores.push(newScore);
        window.localStorage.setItem(
            "highscores",
            JSON.stringify(highscores)
        );
        alert(
            "Your Score has been Submitted"
        );
    }
}

// Save users' score after pressing enter

function checkForEnter(event) {
    if (event.key === "Enter") {
        saveHighscore();
        alert(
            "Your Score has been Submitted"
        );
    }
}
nameEl.onkeyup = checkForEnter;

// Save users' score after clicking submit

submitBtn.onclick = saveHighscore;

// Start quiz after clicking start quiz

startBtn.onclick = quizStart;
